<resources>
    <!-- This file includes all hard-coded information that is displayed in the app-->

    <!-- Reporting steps-->
    <string name="reporting_step1">&lt;b>Step 1&lt;/b> &lt;br/> &lt;br/>Get to a safe place</string>
    <string name="reporting_step2">&lt;b>Step 2&lt;/b> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>Call PCMO/Duty Officer&lt;br/>&lt;br/> &lt;i>All victims of sexual assault are entitled to a medical examination with the PCMO present.  In some cases, forensic exams may be helpful and required to document and collect evidence.  The exams are referred to as a Sexual Assault Forensic Examination or SAFE&lt;/i></string>
    <string name="reporting_step3">&lt;b>Step 3&lt;/b> &lt;br/>&lt;br/> If there are serious injuries, seek immediate treatment</string>
    <string name="reporting_step4">&lt;b>Step 4&lt;/b> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>Do not go to the local police alone&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;i>
-Typically begins with a complaint to local authorities&lt;br/>
-Police may take statements, collect evidence, attempt to establish identity of the offender, develop working theory&lt;br/>
-Police will arrest suspect, conduct identification of suspect&lt;br/>
-Police will present evidence and investigative report to Prosecutor&lt;br/>
-Prosecutor will review evidence and charge suspect if possible&lt;/i></string>
    <string name="reporting_step5">&lt;b>Step 5&lt;/b> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>Protect physical evidence</string>
    <string name="reporting_step6">&lt;b>Step 6&lt;/b> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>Tell someone</string>

    <!-- Reporting FAQ-->
    <string name="reporting_faq1_header">What is the difference between a Restricted Report and a Standard Report?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq1">
        Both types of reports are confidential in nature. Until you provide Peace Corps with your preference, staff will treat your
        information as if you filed a Restricted Report.\n\n

        A Restricted Report limits your information to only those individuals who have a specific need-to-know that information in order
        to provide you with basic services (medical, mental health, or safety).\n\n

        A Standard Report allows you to access all of the same services offered through Restricted Reporting in addition to other support
        services such as filing a police report, switching host families, and changing to a new site. Because additional services
        may be requested, a Standard Report increases the number of people with a need-to-know.
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_faq2_header">Should I choose Standard or Restricted?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq2">
        The choice between filing a Standard or Restricted Report is an individual one. Some services, however, can only be
        offered under standard reporting. Peace Corps believes it can best support you through standard reporting as it allows
        the agency to leverage additional resources and offer additional services such as conducting an in-depth risk assessment.
        The agency recognizes however that for some Volunteers the most important thing is strict confidentiality and a need for
        as few people to know as possible.
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_faq3_header">What does “need-to-know” mean?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq3">
        A need-to-know means that someone has a specific role that requires basic knowledge about the assault. Only service
        providers typically have a need-to-know and therefore have access to information about the assault as reported by you.
        Only medical staff have information about any medical treatment you receive.\n\n

        A role may be mandated by Peace Corps policies and procedures, US law, or local laws. For example, a Country Director has
        a responsibility to know where each Volunteer is located and new site development requires time and resources managed by
        the Country Director. As such, a Country Director has a need-to-know when a Volunteer requests a site change.
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_faq4_header">What if I change my mind later?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq4">
        All reports start as a Restricted Report. A Volunteer can change from Restricted to Standard at any time. Once a report
        becomes Standard, the report cannot be converted back to Restricted because staff that might help provide additional standard
        report services will have been provided with basic information.\n\n
        Volunteers can request additional services at any time, and Volunteers can discontinue/cancel a request for services at any
        time.
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_faq5_header">Will I get the services/type of reporting I want?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq5">
        Volunteer preferences are very important to Peace Corps. We strive to ensure that Volunteer choices are respected. In
        most cases Volunteers receive all the services they desire. Where something is not possible, Peace Corps staff have a
        responsibility to explain why a service is not possible.\n\n

        Because Peace Corps staff members have a responsibility to protect not only you, but other Volunteers, there may be limited
        situations that require the agency to either disclose your name or convert your report from Restricted to Standard.  This is
        most likely in situations where staff believe there is a serious or imminent threat to your health or safety that Peace Corps
        cannot mitigate without additional support or resources. Conversion of a report without a Volunteer’s consent are very rare.
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_faq6_header">What is a SARL?</string>
    <string name="reporting_faq6">
        A SARL is a Sexual Assault Response Liaison. SARLs are typically Peace Corps staff that have had training in how to support
        people that have experienced a sexual assault. SARLs help Volunteers with issues not handled by the PCMO or SSM. For example,
        a SARL might accompany a Volunteer when traveling to an appointment with a local lawyer.
    </string>

    <!-- Details of Other Staff to be contacted in case of crime and the contact number-->
    <string name="reporting_desc_pcsaves">
        The PC SAVES Helpline provides anonymous confidential crisis intervention, support and information to Peace Corps Volunteers
        and trainees who have been affected by sexual assault via a variety of different platforms. All options are staffed by
        trained professionals not affiliated with Peace Corps, available 24/7.  No personally identifying information will be
        collected.\n\n
        Online Chat: pcsaveshelpline.org
    </string>
    <string name="reporting_contact_pcsaves">001 408 844 4357</string>

    <string name="reporting_desc_ova">
        CVictim Advocates are available for Volunteers who are victims of crimes. They can provide information regarding available response services,
        address questions/concerns, and ensure their voices are heard and considered in all decisions affecting service and care.\n\n
        e-mail: victimadvocate@peacecorps.gov
    </string>
    <string name="reporting_contact_ova">202 409 2701</string>

    <string name="reporting_desc_oig">
        OIG is a resource for those who have been harmed by misconduct or criminal wrongdoing by a fellow Volunteer or Peace Corps Staff.
        They are independent from Peace Corps with law enforcement officers who have the unique authorities to help seek a fair resolution and,
        in appropriate cases, to seek prosecution in the United States or host country.\n\n
        e-mail: victimadvocate@peacecorps.gov\n\n
        Learn more: peacecorps.gov/OIG
    </string>
    <string name="reporting_contact_oig">202 692 2915</string>
    
    <string name="reporting_desc_ocrd">
        Resource to provide leadership and guidance on all civil rights, equal employment opportunity and diversity matters; and to address
        issues of discrimination and harassment, including sexual harassment, in the recruitment/service of Volunteers/Trainees.\n\n
        email: ocrd@peacecorps.gov
    </string>
    <string name="reporting_desc_standard"><b>Services available for <i>both Standard and Restricted reports</i> are as follows:</b>\n\n
·	Medical Care related to injury, pregnancy, or sexually transmitted infections\n\n
·	A sexual assault forensic exam (SAFE) to preserve evidence \n\n
·	Counseling from a licensed mental health professional\n\n
·	Medical evacuation\n\n
·	Accompaniment during medical evacuation\n\n
·	Safety planning\n\n
·	Explanation of your legal options\n \n
·	Assistance with making and going to appointments related to the assault (SARL assistance)\n\n
·	Help understanding your rights and ensuring that you receive the services requested (victim advocate assistance)
    </string>
    <string name="reporting_desc_restricted"><b><i>Services only available with a Standard Report</i></b>\n\n
·	Consultation with my Country Director\n\n
·	File a report with local law enforcement\n\n
·	Request a site change\n\n
·	Request a host family change\n\n
·	File a sexual misconduct complaint against another Volunteer/Trainee (Administrative Hearing)\n\n
·	Request the Peace Corps Office of Inspector General conduct an investigation\n\n
·	Request the Peace Corps Office of Civil Rights and Diversity conduct an investigation\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="reporting_contact_ocrd">202 692 2139</string>

    <string name="loc1_name">Uganda</string>
    <string name="loc1_pcmo">1111</string>
    <string name="loc1_ssm">2222</string>
    <string name="loc1_sarl">3333</string>

    <string name="loc2_name">Syria</string>
    <string name="loc2_pcmo">4444</string>
    <string name="loc2_ssm">5555</string>
    <string name="loc2_sarl">6666</string>

    <string name="loc3_name">Tunisia</string>
    <string name="loc3_pcmo">7777</string>
    <string name="loc3_ssm">8888</string>
    <string name="loc3_sarl">9999</string>
</resources>